(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-15T01:58:40.803370",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
Wreaking havoc on the media, she smiles bright
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
There’s a secret that she has that seems to mystify
抜けてるとこさえ彼女のエリア
Always in her area, yet never feeling quite alright
完璧で嘘つきな君は
So perfect as a liar, you are really my
天才的なアイドル様
Flawless, genius idol for life
今日何食べた? 好きな本は?
So, tell me what you ate, the books you read today
遊びに行くならどこに行くの?
And tell me where you’d like to go if only you could play
何も食べてない それは内緒
“I didn’t even eat,” “I’d never spill the beans”
何を聞かれてものらりくらり
No matter what you ask of her, she’ll find a way to flee
そう淡々と だけど燦々と
So plain and meek, but also bright and deep
見えそうで見えない秘密は蜜の味
Those little secrets seem seductive, sweet, and almost clear to see
あれもないないない これもないないない
Well, that’s a no, no, no / And this is no, no, no
好きなタイプは? 相手は? さあ答えて
Come and tell me what’s your type? And what’s he like? / Tell me now, alright?
「誰かを好きになることなんて私分からないからさ」
“Oh, to love and feel so loved, it always seems I alone wouldn’t know what that is or what it means”
嘘か本当か知り得ない
Unaware of what’s the truth and what’s a lie
そんな言葉にまた一人堕ちる
Only for those words that blind, you’re falling deeper till you find
また好きにさせる
You make them love you every time
誰もが目を奪われていく
Everyone, their eyes are taken by your sight
君は完璧で究極のアイドル
You’re a bright, unrivaled, perfect kind of idol
金輪際現れない
None will find another in this life
一番星の生まれ変わり
You’re the first starlight, reborn through the night
その笑顔で愛してるで
Ah, you smile and deceive, you make them all believe
誰も彼も虜にしていく
you really mean “I love you” as you never set them free
その瞳が
And even if those eyes...
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
wreaking havoc on the media, she smiles bright
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
there’s a secret that she has that seems to mystify
抜け出しているところ彼女のエリア
always in her area, yet never feeling quite alright
完璧で嘘つきな君は
so perfect as a liar, you are really my
天才的なアイドル様
flawless, genius idol for life
Good job!
何食べた?
So, tell me what you ate,
好きな本は?
the books you read today,
遊びに行くならどこに行くの?
and tell me where you’d like to go if only you could play?
何も食べてない
"I didn’t even eat,"
それは内緒?
"I’d never spill the beans."
はいはいあの子は特別です
Ah...
我々は端からおまけです
We've always been the extras, left behind.
おこがましいわを引立役B
Acting as a foil to the star on stage.
それ以外じゃないそりゃ臭い
There's no way that everything we have is 'cuz of all her lies.
妬み嫉妬なんてないわけがない
This isn't right!
これはネタじゃないからこそ許せない
You should feel envy you can't hide!
完璧じゃない君じゃ許せない自分を許せない
This isn't fine, this is no joke in my eyes.
誰よりも強い君以外は認めない
I'll never forgive you this time!
誰もが信じ崇めてる
You are so brave and so bright!
まさに最強で無敵のアイドル
Nobody else could ever be mine.
弱いとこなんて見せちゃダメダメ
Everyone is blind, believing all your lies.
知りたくないここは見せずに
You're the best, unrivaled, perfect kind of idol!
唯一無二なんて言わせない
None can find a weakness deep inside,
一番星を宿している
and you take the starlight all through the night!
弱いとこなんて見せちゃダメダメ
She just can't show she's weak,
知りたくないことだけ見せて
'cuz no one really, really wants to know or see
唯一無二じゃなくちゃイヤイヤ
the things she's keeping buried!
それこそ本物の愛
And that's surely, truly, really AI!
得意の笑顔で沸かすメディア
Always stirring up the media, she smiles bright.
隠しきるこの秘密だけは
There’s a secret that she really has to keep inside.
愛してるって嘘で積むキャリア
Lies piling high, till "I love you" is her very life.
これこそ私なりの愛だ
That’s exactly just the kind of love I’m calling mine!
流れる汗も綺麗なアクア
Through the sweat, you shine,
ルビーを隠したこの瞼
that this eyelid hides.
舞台踊り舞う私はマリア
Singing and then dancing, I am Mary and I'm so divine!
そう嘘はとびきりの愛だ
Yeah, just the finest love is made from pretty lies!
誰かに愛されたことも
Someone to love, someone to be loved...
誰かのこと愛したこともない
None of that is true, but I believe it anyway.
そんな私の嘘だいつか本当にになること信じている
Someday, I'm sure I'll have it all.
いつかきっと全部手に入れる私はそう欲張りなアイドル
I'm a greedy kind of idol!
同じ頼戴してみんなのことちゃんと言いしたいから
To my darling little ones, through the sweat, you shine.
今日も嘘をつくの
To my precious little ones...
この言葉がいつか本当になる日を願って
That this eyelid hides.
それでもまだ君と君にだけは言えずにいたけど
Singing and then dancing, I am Mary!
あ、やっと言えたこれは絶対嘘じゃない愛してる
Yeah, just the finest love is made from pretty lies!
みんな！今回は！
Everyone, thank you so much for coming to...
博衣こより2周年記念ライブを
Hakui Koyori's 2nd Anniversary Live!
見に来てくれてありがとうございます！すいえい！
Thank you so much! Yay!
今回のテーマは「Memories & Future」！
Today's theme is "Memories & Future"!
たくさんの思い出を振り返りながら
Looking back on a lot of memories,
そして、1曲目は歌ってみたを出した「アイドル」を
And for the first song, I sang "Idol"!
歌って踊らせていただきましたけれども、どうだったー？
I got to sing and dance to it, but how was it?
いや、この曲はもう歌もダンスもめちゃめちゃ難しい曲で
This song is super, super difficult for both singing and dancing.
歌ってみたを出したのも結構挑戦な気持ちだったので、
Putting out a cover of it was quite a challenge,
大切な1曲として歌いました！
so I sang it as a very important song!
それでは
Now then,
続いては、さっそくゲストコーナーに行こうと思います！
next up, we'll finally be heading to the guest corner!
いろんな思い出を
We'll be looking back with various memories...
それでは、どうぞー！
Well then, please!
あなたのアイドル
Your idol,
サインはB♡
The sign is B!
(B小町！フフー！)
(B-Komachi! Fufuu!)
ようやく会えたね 嬉しいね
We finally met, I'm so happy!
待ち遠しくて足をバタバタさせながら
Waiting for so long, tapping my feet excitedly,
今日楽しみで眠れなかったよ
I was too excited to sleep last night!
(俺も〜！)
(Me too!)
緊張なんしてる場合じゃない
This isn't the time to be nervous!
一分一秒無駄になんてできない
We can't waste a single second!
さあはじめましょう
So let's get started!
君も！君も！君も！
You too, you too, you too!
お待たせー様
Welcome, esteemed guest!
手を鳴らせ いらっしゃいませ
Make some noise, welcome!
「好き」が集まる場所へようこそ！
Welcome to where passions gather!
日常は苦労苦難の中
Everyday life is full of hardships,
ここに来たなら踊らなきゃ損！損！損！
If you're here, you've gotta dance!
人がいようがまいが関係ない
It doesn't matter who else is around,
箱が大きい小さいとか気にしない
Size of the stage doesn't matter at all!
ねえ アナタには 見えない事ばかり
Why, you have many sides that are only hidden from my sight
アタシは 見えている事を知らないの？
But I'm always watching right here with eyes open quite wide
背中につけられた 誰かのキスの跡
On your back, a little mark shows somebody had kissed you, like so
一人じゃ買う訳の無い それも
That's not something that appears on its own, don't you know?
見て見ぬふりなだけ
I'll pretend I never saw it though
バイバイ
Bye babe
笑っちまう程に キュートなカノジョ
She's got you bound, a girl so cute that you laugh aloud
常時奔放 狂気 短気
Out of her mind, with a temper short on time
怒鳴ってだって 目が合って 一撃
Though you may shout, when both your eyes meet, it's over now
バイバイ
Bye bye
ねえ 精神から 全身まで
From body to your deep mind
表面から 内面まで
From your surface to your insides
脳天から 先端まで
From your tiptoes to your full height
知りたいの それから
Wanna know your whole life
最近聞いた 音楽から
And again, from music that you like, then to the bills
散財した 総額まで
you've tossed aside
完全把握しないと 気が済まないの
Still I know I won't feel satisfied yet till I make you all mine
とにかく 言ったって 実際の問題は
Every day, you have complaints, you still claim your real pain
その眼中 アタシ何割くらい担ってるか
only came from feeling the weight my presence makes and the space that I take
呻吟隠さないで 確信を頂戴
Oh, don't you hide it that way! Reassure me, okay?
されど黙って 語らず
That said, be quiet and just do as I say
バイバイ
Bye bye
困っちまう程に キュートなカノジョ
She's got you bound, a girl so cute that you're maddened now
容姿端麗 蠱惑 甘美
Charming outside, with a figure all would like
身勝手だって 泣く シックな素振り
She cries aloud, a little sick habit that she found
瞬時酔狂 女冥利
Drunken in time, that's a woman's joy to find
愛していいのさ 強く愛していいのさ
Still, you will love me, right? 'Cuz you can't help that you love me, right?
過去を啜る程に ポップなエナジー
The past hits deep, there's so much pop from that elegy
排気口から 匂うラーメン
Follow your nose, where the ramen scent arose
騙され奪われる恋でもいいの
There may be thieves that rob our love, but no matter, see
だってこの声は
That's 'cuz my voice is just so –
スーパーデュパー甘々キュート、なのを？
Super duper sweetly cute, no?
笑っちまう程に キュートなカノジョ
She's got you bound, a girl so cute that you laugh aloud
常時奔放 狂気 短気
Out of her mind, with a temper short on time
怒鳴ってだって 目が合って 一撃
Though you may shout, when both your eyes meet, it's over now
洗脳完了 女上手
Skilled and refined, she has brainwashed you inside
人が嫌おうが 今更関係ない
Whether people hate me or not, it doesn't matter now
ハートが大きか 小さいとか気にしない
Whether hearts are big or small, I don't care at all
ちゃんと 見えてる
Now you can see it clearly
キミのサリウム
Yourarium
今ふと吹けば飛ぶような
Floating away like a breath of wind
小さな小さなサイロをだけど
A tiny, tiny silo, but even so
アタシを押してくれないなら
If you won't push me forward
爆レスを上げる あなたのアイドル
I'll give you maximum fanservice, your idol
サイウァビー
Sign is B
我爱你 酔いが覚めない
Wo ai ni, my intoxication won't fade away
我爱你 恋が覚めない
Wo ai ni, this love won't fade away
我爱你 お生憎様の慣れ果て察して
Wo ai ni, behold the pathetic ruin of your darling!
無問題 破滅してみてホミー
Mumondai, try experiencing ruin, homie
タイト トラウマの味も反対
Tight, even the taste of trauma is opposed
お手お座りでハイ 報酬
Sit down and give a paw, high reward
喉の奥がチクンチクン
A prickling deep in my throat
僕はドクンドクン
My heart goes thump-thump
鼓動で孤独消してみてよ
Try erasing my loneliness with your heartbeat
愛も恋も独占して
Monopolize both love and romance
僕を独占して
Monopolize me entirely
このまま中毒になるまでチューしよう
Let's kiss until we become addicted like this
そして Get get get on Get get get on chu!
And get, get, get on, get, get, get on, chu!
熱くとろけるくらいに溢れた気持ちがたまらないでしょ
The overflowing feelings warm enough to melt you are irresistible, right?
Get get get on Get get get on chu!
我爱你 無問題 Get get get on chu!
Wo ai ni, mumondai, get get get on chu!
ポンチーカン 勝負はいつもドンチンカン
Pon-chi-kan, the match is always clash-crash
僕に言わせりゃちんぷんかん
To hear me tell it, it's all gibberish
ぷんだ最後はロンでしょ？
Punda, the end is ron, right?
もう何回？ 殺されればいい
How many times? Just kill me already
Oh, One night 忘れられない
Oh, One night, unforgettable
Oh, One night 終わらないでトキメキ偏愛予報
Oh, One night, don't end, obsessive love forecast
喉の奥がチクンチクン
A prickling deep in my throat
僕はドクンドクン
My heart goes thump-thump
心臓ごと引きずり出してみてよ
Try dragging out my heart along with it
きもちいい
"Feels so good,"
ねえめんどくさいけど
even though it's a pain,
やっぱ照れくさいけど
even though it's kinda embarrassing,
死ぬまで忘れられないチューしよ
let's kiss till we die, one we'll never forget.
いかれた街はゾンビで溢れる
The crazed town overflows with zombies,
君は僕に恋してる
you're in love with me,
ときめく胸に繋がるロープを引っ張りなよ
so pull the rope connected to your throbbing heart.
いくよ
Here we go!
Bet bet bet on! Bet bet bet on! Bet on chu!
本気で狂えるくらいの夢々しさが美しいでしょ
A dreamy madness that makes you truly crazy—isn't it beautiful?
Get get get on! Get get get on! Get on chu!
せーの、ポン・チー・カン終わんない Get get get on chu!
Ready, pon, chi, kan—it never ends! Get get get on chu!
ほらね
See?
我愛你
Wo ai ni,
無問題
mōmantai!
Get get get on chu!
こより、どうぞ。
Koyori, here you go.
とても辛い調味料をたっぷり使った一品だよ！
It's a dish packed with super spicy seasoning!
辛くないよ！
It's not spicy at all!
なんでも爆解！こよりちゃん
Anything Solved! Koyori-chan
電波テンポアップして絶賛感電中！
Radio wave tempo up, currently getting electrocuted!
あなたにもわすれたいこと　かなしいこと　あるのかしらね
I wonder if there are things you want to forget, or things that make you sad, too.
知らない映画なのに涙をながすのは　ドラマチックが足りないからよ
Shedding tears at a movie you don't even know is because there's not enough drama.
そんな愚にも付かないこと　くだらないこと　考えてばかりね
You're always thinking about such silly, pointless things.
雨が上がれば愛もその横顔も　誰かのものになるのでしょう
When the rain stops, both love and that profile will probably become someone else's.
嘘っパチのファンデーションも全部　今夜のためよ
All this fake foundation is just for tonight.
なのに一体全体如何して何故々って
Yet why on earth, how, and why is that?
不安定なカンテラどこまで行くの
This unstable lantern, how far will it go?
あなた一切合祭放り去ってもう
Throwing away everything about you, enough!
冗談じゃないわ
I'm not joking around!
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ　その時が来たってどうにもなんないぜ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous, even if that time comes, there's nothing we can do.
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリカするだけ
Vague truths only make things melancholic.
あたしをさっさらって今テイクオンミー
Snatch me away and take me on now, take on me!
はあ　ちゃんちゃらおかしな法ばっかで食指がびくともしないわ
Ha, with all these ridiculous laws, my appetite won't even budge.
実態の無い感情放っといたって戦略なんてありゃせぬのに何故
Emotions with no substance left behind—why is there no strategy?
ああもう懲り懲りよ　あたしの喝となる気質もじっと堪えて取り繕っては
Ah, I'm sick of it. My temperament that turns to scolding, patiently enduring and putting up a front,
とうとう臨界点
finally reaching a critical point.
年が年中リップサービス　どんがらガシャイン　フィールガールは涙の目にも鬼
Lip service all year round, clanging and crashing, feel girls are demons even through teary eyes.
今や頭の中のミュージックのせいであなたの話は一向に聴き取れない　少しは真当なこと言ってよ
Now, because of the music in my head, I can't hear a word you're saying. Say something sensible for once!
回り出すターンテーブル　ぜんぶ忘れさせてよ
The turntable starts to spin, make me forget everything.
だが一体全体如何して何故々って
Yet why on earth, how, and why is that?
不安定なカンテラ消えないままで
The unstable lantern remains unextinguished.
あなた一口両舌食い違ってもう
You're speaking out of both sides of your mouth, we're completely at odds!
冗談じゃないわ
I'm not joking around!
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ　その時が来たってどうにもなんないぜ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous, even if that time comes, there's nothing we can do.
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリカするだけ
Vague truths only make things melancholic.
あたしをさっさらって今テイクオンミー
Snatch me away and take me on now, take on me!
冗談じゃないわ
I'm not joking around!
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ　その時が来たってどうにもなんないぜ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous, even if that time comes, there's nothing we can do.
不甲斐ないわ　感情なんてランドリーで落とすだけ
It's pathetic, just washing away emotions in the laundry.
あたしと確かめ合ってイエローマジック
Confirming with me, yellow magic!
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ　その時が来たってどうにもなんないぜ
Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous, even if that time comes, there's nothing we can do.
曖昧な本当なんてメランコリカするだけ
Vague truths only make things melancholic.
あたしをさっさらって今テイクオンミー
Snatch me away and take me on now, take on me!
ハロー・バイバイはいつもセット
Hello and goodbye are always a set.
手を伸ばしたら遠ざかって
When I reach out my hand, you pull away.
引き攣った顔を戻して
Putting back my twitching face,
モヤモヤ消化エンドレス
endless digestion of vague worries.
近付かれたら離れたくなって
When you get close, I want to get away,
頼らなくても平気なんです
and I'm fine even without relying on anyone.
ちょっと待って誰も頷かない
Wait a second, nobody is nodding.
ハロー×バイバイ は いつも セット
Hello x goodbye are always a set,
手 を 伸ばし たら 遠ざかっ て
reaching out only to find you too far.
引き摺っ た 顔 を 戻し て
Pulling back, I put on my usual face,
モヤモヤ 消化 エンドレス
hazy and vague, an endless loop.
近付か れ たら 離れ たく なっ て
Getting close makes me want to pull away,
頼ら なく て も 平気 な ん です
even without reliance, I'm just fine.
ちょっと 待っ て 誰も 咎め ない
Wait a second, nobody's blaming me,
これじゃ お手上げ状態
so this is me throwing my hands up.
笑顔 作れ ば 色めき立っ て きっと 惹かれ合う はず の 法則
If I put on a smile, things start to brighten up, surely drawn together by the rules of it all.
なんで ？ 響か ない
Why doesn't it resonate?
難解 過ぎる 愛 の 方程式
An equation of love that's far too complex.
焦っ て 曖昧 な 答え 出す 必要 は ない
No need to rush and force out ambiguous answers.
理解 でき ない 性質 だって
It's just the nature of it, unable to understand.
不安定 も 歓迎 片足 で 立っ て
Uncertainty is welcome, standing on one foot,
アンバランス が 僕 の 証明
this imbalance is my proof.
笑え ない ぐちゃぐちゃ な 感情 の 正体 ？ 持ち帰っ て 膨れ上がる 後悔 真面目 さ 故 バカ 見る って なに ？
Unable to even smile, what is the core of these messy emotions? Carrying them back, regrets swelling up, looking foolish for being too earnest—what's this?
これじゃ お手上げ状態
So this is me throwing my hands up.
ほんと は それほど 強く ない から
The truth is, I'm not really that strong,
平気 じゃ ない 大丈夫 じゃ ない なんで ？
I'm not okay, I'm not all right. Why?
言え ない
I just can't say it.
正解 ない 愛 の 方程式
An equation of love with no right answers.
振り回さ れ て 消耗 し て も ナンセンス
Even if I'm tossed around and worn out, it's nonsense.
反発 し たい わけ じゃ ない
It's not like I want to rebel.
わかっ てる のに 肝心 な とこ で
Even though I know, right when it matters most,
アンバランス な 僕 の 性根
this unbalanced nature is who I am.
明快 だ 感情 の 実態 本当 の 愛 知りたくて 無理やり でも 側 に 来 て
Cheerfully realizing my true emotions, I just want to know real love, so even if it's forced, come stay by my side.
難解 過ぎる 愛 の 方程式
An equation of love that's far too complex.
焦っ て 曖昧 な 答え 出す 必要 は ない
No need to rush and force out ambiguous answers.
理解 でき ない 性質 だって
It's just the nature of it, unable to understand.
不安定 も 歓迎 片足 で 立っ て
Uncertainty is welcome, standing on one foot,
支え て い て よ 僕 の 正体
please support me, my true self.
アンバランス が 僕 の 証明
This imbalance is my proof.
えー、という こと で ゲスト と の 曲 3 曲 と なんと ここ で 初 お披露目！
And so, that was three songs with our guests! And what do you know, we had our very first reveal here!
新しい オリジナル 曲 を 歌わ せ て いただき まし た！ どう だっ たー？
We got to perform a brand new original song! How was it?
えー、ゲスト パート で は コンコ よ 24 や ゲーム 大会 コラボ で お世話 に なっ た 皆さん に ゲスト に お越し いただき まし た！ ありがとう ござい まーす！
For the guest part, thank you so much to everyone who came to visit us from Konko You 24 and the game tournament collaboration!
パフォーマンス し たかっ た 曲 を 一緒 に 歌え て めちゃめちゃ 嬉しかっ た です！
I'm super, super happy we got to sing the songs we wanted to perform together!
みんな も コメント 、 拍手 とか で 盛り上げ て くれ て 本当 ありがとうー！
Thank you so much to everyone for hyping us up in the comments and with applause!
そして 、 新 オリジナル 曲 は 「 アンバランス 」 と いう タイトル です！
And now, the brand new original song is titled "Unbalance"!
えー 、 こちら は 最近 だ と リコリコ の オープニング の アライブ など を 手掛け て いらっしゃる 茂永 亮介 さん に お 作り いただき まし た！
This one was recently produced for us by Ryosuke Shigenaga, who also worked on RikoRiko's opening theme and other tracks!
こより 初めて の 「 恋 」 を テーマ に し た 曲 と なっ て おり ます！
It's a song themed around Koyori's very first love!
えー 、 恋 が よく わから ない ぶきっちょ な 女の子 の 心情 を 、 え 、 僕 かっこよく 仕上げ まし た ので 、 後で じっくり 歌詞 も 堪能 し て ね！
We managed to coolly capture Koyori's awkward, hard-to-understand teenage girl feelings, so I hope you'll enjoy the lyrics in detail later!
えー 、 この 曲 は です ね 、 ライブ 終了 後 に すぐ MV が プレミア 公開 24 時間 から リリース さ れ まーす！
Now, this song will be released on streaming platforms 24 hours after the live ends!
ぜひ ヘビロテ し て くださーい！
Be sure to check it out on heavy rotation!
それ で は 、 この 後 は ソロ 曲 、 そして コラボ パート を 続け て お 楽しみ ください！
Well then, please continue to enjoy the solo songs and the collaboration parts after this!
で は 、 次 の 曲 の 準備 を し ます！
Now, time to get ready for the next song...
なん と 、 男子 の ガチ 恋 距離 準備 タ イー ム！ いえーい！ おー！
And it's... serious mode! Get serious Koyori preparation time! Yay!
もう 準備 が でき た みたい ！ で は 行き ます よ！
The preparation seems to be all done, so let's go!
と いう こと で 、 聞い て ください 。 「 あるけみー 」
And with that, please listen to "Arukemi"!
無限に生きたい
I want to live infinitely.
無限に生きられたら 全て叶う
If I could live infinitely, everything would come true.
でもいろんなものが あたしを追い詰めてく
But all kinds of things are driving me into a corner.
生きる残り時間 夢の座標 行方
The remaining time to live, my dream's coordinates, where I'm headed—
全部大事なものなのに
they're all such important things.
いいさここでちょっと 甘いもの食べていこう
Fine, let's stay here for a bit and eat something sweet.
そういう思考停止ばかり得意になった
I've only gotten good at shutting down my thoughts like that.
歩いてきた道 振り返えると
When I look back on the path I've walked down,
イヤなことばかりでもううんざりだよ
it's nothing but things I hated, and I'm already sick of it.
触れるものを 輝かせていく
A path where I make the things I touch shine—
そんな道を 生きてきたかったよ
that's the kind of life I wanted to live.
無性に生きたい
I desperately want to live.
焦ってばかりの日々 全て消えそう
Days of nothing but rushing, everything feels like it's vanishing.
でもサボってみる だって疲れていっちゃうじゃん
But I'll try slacking off, because otherwise I'll just get exhausted.
そんな矛盾思考 あたし頭どっか知らないうち打ったみたいだ
With such contradictory thoughts, it's like I hit my head somewhere without realizing it.
いっそここでちょっと 病院へ行こうとこう
Let's go straight to the hospital from here for a little checkup.
ずっと起きていられる薬は置いていませんか?
Don't you have some medicine that will keep me awake forever?
ぼさっと突っ立っているだけでもう
Just standing there blankly,
化石になってしまいそうなんだよ
it feels like I'm about to turn into a fossil.
誰からも忘れられたような ぐすんだ存在になってしまうよ
I'm becoming a dull existence, as if forgotten by everyone.
いいさここでちょっと 根性を見せてやる
All right, I'll show you some grit right here.
自分で作って 存在の証明へ
Slapping my own cheeks as proof of my existence!
歩いてきた道 振り返らない
I won't look back on the path I've walked down.
イヤなことばかりでも前へ進め
Even if it's all things I hated, I'll move forward.
触れるものを 輝かせていく そんな存在になってみせるよ
I'll become an existence that makes the things I touch shine!
ボサッと言葉紡いでるだけで
Just spinning words blankly,
過激になってしまいそうなんだよ
it feels like I'm about to become too extreme.
誰からも忘れられたような ぐすんだ存在になってしまうよ
I'm becoming a dull existence, as if forgotten by everyone.
いいさ ここで ちょっと 根性を見せてやる
All right, I'll show you some grit right here.
自分 で ほっぺた叩いて 存在の証明へ
Slapping my own cheeks as proof of my existence!
歩いてきた道 振り返らない
I won't look back on the path I've walked down.
イヤなことばかりでも 前へ進め
Even if it's all things I hated, I'll move forward.
触れるものを輝かせていく そんな存在になってみせるよ
I'll become an existence that makes the things I touch shine!
歩いてきた道 振り返らない
I won't look back on the path I've walked down.
イヤなことばかりでも 前へ進め
Even if it's all things I hated, I'll move forward.
触れるものを輝かせていく そんな存在になってみせるよ
I'll become an existence that makes the things I touch shine!
そんな存在になってみせるよ
I'll become that kind of existence!
見せるよ
I'll show you!
神様に恋をしていた頃は
When I was still in love with God,
こんな別れが来るとは思っていなかったよ
I never expected such a farewell would come.
もう二度と触れられないなら
If I could never feel your touch again,
神様に恋をしていた頃は
When I was still in love with God,
こんな別れが来るとは思っていなかったよ
I never thought such a farewell would come.
もう二度と触れられないならせめて最後に もう一度抱きしめて欲しかったよ
If I could never touch you again, I just wanted to be held tight one last time.
It's long long good-bye...
さようなら さようなら 何度だって
Goodbye, goodbye, how many times...
自分に 無上に 言い聞かせて
I told myself over and over.
手を振るのは優しさだよね?
Waving goodbye is just being kind, right?
今強さが欲しい
Now I want to be stronger.
貴方に出逢い STAR輝いて アタシが生まれて
Meeting you, the stars shone, and I was born.
愛すればこそ 愛あればこそ
To love is to live; love is all there is.
希望のない 奇跡を待って どうなるの?
What's the point of waiting for a hopeless miracle?
涙に染む 惑星の輝きは gone...
The planet's glow is lost in tears.
忘れないよ 貴方の温もりも
I will never forget your warmth,
その優しさも 全て包んでくれた両手も
your kindness, and your embracing hands.
It's long long good-bye...
さようなら さようなら 愛しい人
Goodbye, goodbye, my beloved.
貴方が いたから 歩いてこれた
I made it this far because of you.
ひとりなんかじゃなかったよね?
I wasn't alone, was I?
今答えが欲しい
Now I want an answer.
燃える様な流星 捕まえて 火を灯して
Catch a falling star, light a fire,
愛していたい 愛されていたい
I want to love and be loved.
冷えたカラダひとつで 世界は どうなるの?
What can a freezing body do in this world?
張り続けてた 虚勢が溶けていく long for...
The facade I kept up is melting away...
どうしてなの? 涙溢れて 止められない
Why can't I stop these overflowing tears?
貴方に出逢い STAR輝いて アタシが生まれて
Meeting you, the stars shone, and I was born.
愛すればこそ 愛あればこそ
To love is to live; love is all there is.
希望のない 奇跡を待って どうなるの?
What's the point of waiting for a hopeless miracle?
涙に染む 惑星の輝きは gone...
The planet's glow is lost in tears.
もし生まれ変わって また巡り逢えるなら
If I'm reborn and we meet again,
その時もきっと アタシを見つけ出して
please find me then,
もう二度と離さないで 捕まえてて
and never let me go again.
ひとりじゃないと 囁いて欲しい planet...
Whisper to me that I am not alone.
貴方に出逢い STAR輝いて アタシが生まれて
Meeting you, the stars shone, and I was born.
愛すればこそ 愛あればこそ
To love is to live; love is all there is.
希望のない 奇跡を待って どうなるの?
What's the point of waiting for a hopeless miracle?
涙に染む 惑星の輝きは gone...
The planet's glow is lost in tears.
星の瞬きは 虫生まれ変わって
The planet's pulse keeps changing,
また巡り逢えるなら
and if we can meet again,
その時もきっと
at that time, for sure...
アタシを見つけ出して もう二度と離さないで
If I find you, I'll never let you go again,
捕まえてて
catching you and never letting you go.
ひとりじゃないと 囁いて欲しい planet...
Whisper to me that I'm not alone...
こよちゃん、一緒に歌おう！
Koyori-chan, let's sing together!
え？
Eh?
この曲を？いいんですか？
This song? Is it alright?
うぇーい！嬉しすぎてもう…爆発！
Yay! I'm so happy I could... explode!
こよちゃん！
Koyori-chan!
いのち
Inochi
でも歌わないの 息をしている よう に見えている
Yet I don't sing, even as it looks like I'm breathing
性能の裏側 私にとってのなにか
Behind the performance, something precious to me
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heartbeat thumps away
戦っても腐らずに ここで歌うよ
without rotting even in battle, I will sing right here
ボタンひとつのいのち
A life on a single button
最後まで私のこと覚えててくれるの
Will you remember me until the very end?
消えてしまいそうなの 分かってよ 分かってよね
It feels like I'm about to fade away, understand that, won't you?
本当どこなの 恋と愛を誓い合んでしょ
Where on earth are we? We swore to each other in love
君が忘れちゃったら私は無くなるの
if you forget me, I'll disappear
いのちのような夢を見てる またねバイバイ
Dreaming a dream like life, see you later, bye-bye
息をしている 泣かないで生きている
I am breathing, living without crying
自己証明を欲しがって欲しがっているんだ
wanting and craving self-proof
音が止まって 動かなくなって
When the sound stops and I stop moving
そんな私を 君は笑ってくれるかな
will you smile at a me like that?
鼓動がドクドクしている
My heartbeat thumps away
嫌われても腐らずに ここで歌うよ 気分がいいの
without rotting even if hated, I will sing right here, I feel good
いのち
Life
気分がいいの
I feel good
最後まで私のこと見届けてくれるの
will you watch over me until the end?
覚めてしまいそうなの 分かってよ 分かってよね
It feels like I'm about to wake up, understand that, won't you?
声が凍えるんだ よじょうのない涙が出ちゃうほど
My voice is freezing, to the point where uncontained tears flow out
君が忘れちゃったら私は無くなるの
if you forget me, I'll disappear
いのちのような夢を見てる またねバイバイ
Dreaming a dream like life, see you later, bye-bye
塞ぎ込んだあの日を 軽くいじらないで
Don't lightly meddle with that gloomy day
やめて
stop it
それが生きる勝手になる からだ
That's why it becomes the reason to live
大丈夫 ずっと私は歌い続けるから
It's alright, because I will keep on singing forever
最後まで私は生きているか分からないけど
I don't know if I'll live until the very end
君がくれた言葉は確かに残ってる
but the words you gave me definitely remain
最後まで私のこと覚えててくれるの
Will you remember me until the very end?
ピッチ死んでしまうだる 分からない 分からないよね
Pitch is dying, I don't know, I don't know, right?
痛いくらい気持ちがシンクロするときもあるけど
Sometimes our feelings synchronize to a painful degree
君が忘れちゃったら私は無くなるの
but if you forget me, I'll disappear
いのちのような夢を見てる またねバイバイ
Dreaming a dream like life, see you later, bye-bye
新球観戦 楽しいですね！
Watching new baseball games is so much fun!
そうでしょう！ こやもホームラン打ってみたいの！
Right? Koya wants to hit a home run too!
あっ？
Huh?
これだー！
This is it!
やめろー！
Stop it!
背番号1のすごい奴が相手
A great guy with uniform number 1 is the opponent
フラミンゴみたいひょいと一本足で
Like a flamingo, standing on one leg
スーパースターのお出ましに
For the superstar's entrance
ベンチのサインは敬遠だけど
The bench's sign is intentional walk, but
逃げるのは嫌だわ
I hate running away
男ならここで逃げの手一筋だけど
If you're a man, that's the only escape route, but
女にはそんなことはできはしない
A woman can't do such a thing
弱気なサインに首を振り 得意の魔球を投げ込むだけよ
Shake my head at the timid sign, just throwing my magic ball
さあ勝負よ勝負よ
Come on, let's fight!
しんと静まったスタジアム
A quietly hushed stadium
世紀の一瞬よ
A moment of the century
熱い勝負は恋の気分よ
A heated match feels like love
胸の鼓動がどきどき目先はくらくら
Heart pounding, eyes spinning
負けそう 負けそう
Going to lose, going to lose
私 ピンクのサウスポー
My pink southpaw
きりきり舞いよ きりきり舞いよ 魔球は魔球はハリケーン
Spinning around, spinning around, the magic ball is a hurricane
背番号1のすごい奴が笑う
The great guy with uniform number 1 laughs
お嬢ちゃん投げてみろと奴が笑う
The guy laughs, telling the girl to try throwing
しばらくお色気さようなら でっかい相手をしとめるまでは
Goodbye for a while to sexiness, until you take down the big opponent
ちょっとおあずけ
Just a little wait
さっと駆け抜けるサスペンス
Suspense that quickly runs through
スリル の瞬間よ
The moment of thrill
熱い視線がからみ合ったら
When hot gazes entangle
白い火花がパチパチ 心はめらめら燃えそう燃えそう
White sparks crackle, hearts burn and flicker
私 ピンクのサウスポー
My pink southpaw
きりきり舞いよ きりきり舞いよ 魔球は魔球はハリケーン
Spinning around, spinning around, the magic ball is a hurricane
プロテト大会で背中を押してくれたペコラ先輩に、お礼がしたいの！
I want to thank Pekora-senpai for supporting me!
好きなもの…好きなもの…
Favorite things... favorite things...
爆破好きですよね！
You love explosions, right?!
やめろー！やめろー！
Stop it! Stop it!
なんでも爆解！こよりチャン
[Title: Anything Explosion! Koyori-chan]
この混沌とした令和のインターネットを照らす一筋の光
A ray of light illuminating the chaotic internet of Reiwa
電子の海を漂うオタクに笑顔を
Bringing smiles to otaku drifting in the electronic sea
未来の平和をお約束
Promising peace for the future
躁鬱だけどまかせとけ
Manic-depressive, but leave it to me
インターネット・エンジェル ただいま降臨！
Internet Angel, descending right now!
社会をやめろ 家族をやめろ 人間関係をやめろ
Quit society, quit family, quit human relations
今すぐ薄暗い部屋で青白いライトを浴びろ
Bathe in pale blue light in a dim room right now
大丈夫わかったこと全部上書きするからね
It's okay, I'll overwrite everything I understood
現実よりも crazy for you
Crazy for you than reality
おかしくなりそうなほど情報過多のインターネット
Information-overloaded internet enough to make you crazy
今たすけてあげるよダーリン
I'll save you right now, darling
ダーリン ダーリン
Darling, darling,
ウソはウソであると見抜けるし
Lies can be seen through as lies,
この愛は暴走しちゃうし 壊れてしまうけど
and this love runs wild and breaks down, but...
考えなくていいんだよ
You don't have to think about it.
もうすぐ楽になるから
You'll feel better soon.
脳内に乱反射する poison radio
Poison radio scattering across your brain,
麻薬より甘いよ
sweeter than any drug.
いいね 良くないね キミにとっては毒だね
Good, not good, it's poison to you.
いいね 良くないね それでも飲むんだね
Good, not good, yet you still drink it.
いいね 良くないね 二人の秘密だね
Good, not good, our little secret.
私だけ見ててね
Only look at me.
まるで天使のように微笑む強めの幻 internet girl
Smiling like an angel, a strong illusion internet girl,
そして悪魔みたいにささやくあなただけのデパス needy girl
and whispering like a demon, your one and only needy girl.
浅い眠りと承認欲求のオーバードーズ
Shallow sleep and an overdose of need for approval,
脳天直撃する私たちだけの宗教とヒカリ
our own religion and light striking straight to the brain.
倫理より激しく生きた宇宙すら侵食する恋
A love living fiercer than ethics, corroding even the universe,
何度も送られる毒電波を優しさだけで包んで
wrapping the poison waves sent time and again solely in kindness.
逆さまのコンピュータと断片的なカウンセリング
An upside-down computer and fragmentary counseling,
きらめく屋上で奏でた夢見心地の旋律
a dreamy melody played on the sparkling rooftop,
夕暮れ時にさよならの練習をして 壊して愛して許して
practicing goodbyes at twilight—break it, love it, forgive it,
狂って狂って狂って甘く狂わせて
go crazy, go crazy, make me go sweetly crazy.
ゆらぎ始める世界 曖昧になる風景
The world begins to waver, the scenery becomes ambiguous,
あなただけが映っているメモリー 神様なんていないよ
memories reflecting only you—there is no such thing as God.
このふざけたインターネットは七色のサイケデリック
This absurd internet is a seven-colored psychedelic,
SNSという瓶詰地獄に救済を
bringing salvation to the bottled hell called SNS.
過去の歴史は見ないフリ あなたのためのすぐそばに
Pretending not to see past history, right by your side just for you,
インターネット・エンジェル かわいい参上！
Internet Angel, cutely arriving!
まるで天使のように抱きつく強めの幻 internet girl
Holding tight like an angel, a strong illusion internet girl,
そして悪魔みたいにキスするあなただけの2d girl
and kissing like a demon, your one and only 2D girl.
INTERNET OVERDOSE
信じ合う仲間といっしょに
Together with friends who trust each other,
挑戦ののろしを上げよう 終わらない青春の
let's raise the beacon of challenge, in our never-ending youth!
青春アーカイブ
Youth Archive!
走り出す 主人公捨てて 飛び込め みんなで空へワープしよう
Running out, leaving the protagonist behind, diving in, let's warp together into the sky!
浸かる 水滴 こぼれ落ちて 青春を感じている もうすぐ
Soaking in water droplets spilling over, feeling our youth, soon...
あちゅ！ 成長した姿を見せた 二人は完璧
Achoo! Showing our grown-up selves, we're totally perfect,
本番はもっと全力で はい！はい！はい！ふー！
and the real show is with even more all-out energy—one, two, three, woo!
大切な思い出で 傷だらけ歩くけどね まだ
Walking covered in scars of precious memories, but still,
感情に浸かってる暇はない
there's no time to get lost in emotion.
人生最大の恋が始まる
The greatest love of a lifetime begins!
勝ち取った景色は遠い
The scenery we won is far away,
逃げるな 崖越えて 僕らはまだチャレンジャー
don't run away, cross the cliff, we are still challengers!
冷たい声に溺れたって かすかなの
Even if we drown in cold voices, our faint...
涙を拭い寄せるように
As if wiping away tears...
期待外れだと誰かが嘆く
Someone complains that it fell short of expectations,
痛いと痛いがいつも戦う
as pain and pain always fight.
プライドだけを頼りに抗う
Struggling, relying only on pride,
自分を信じたい
I want to believe in myself.
努力は報われる
Hard work pays off—
笑いたい奴は笑ってろ
let those who want to laugh, laugh.
喧騒に浸ってる暇はない
There's no time to get lost in the noise.
今世紀最大の
The biggest romance
恋が始まる
of this century is beginning.
反響が足りない もっともっと
The echo isn't enough, more and more!
後悔はさせない
We won't let you regret it!
想像の果てにある高み
The heights at the end of our imagination...
勝ち取った景色は遠い
The scenery we won is far away.
逃げるな限界の壁越えて
Don't run away, break through the wall of limits—
僕らはまだチャレンジ中
we're still in the middle of the challenge!
一緒に歌ってくださったゲストの皆さん、本当にありがとうございます！
To all the guests who sang along with me, thank you so much!
それでは続いて、未来へ繋げていく、
Next, connecting to the future—
本日2曲目の新しいオリジナル曲でーーす！
it's my second new original song of the day!
なんと今回こよ初めて歌詞に挑戦いたしました！
This time, Koyori actually tried writing the lyrics for the first time!
みんなへの応援ソングです！聞いてください、「ティアゲイザー」！
It's an cheering song for everyone! Please listen: "Tear-Gazer"!
ぽつり漏れた 幸せが逃げ
Happiness spilled and slipped away,
ちゃいそうで映った吐息
looking like it's about to vanish in my sigh.
ねえ鏡の中 無理な笑顔に 滲み出る優柔不断
Hey, in the mirror, my forced smile leaks out my indecision.
どうしてぼくだけうまくいかないのかな
Why is it that only I can't get things right?
ひとりよがりだとはわかってる (わかるよ)
I know I'm being selfish. (I know)
自信をなくして 崩れ落ちたとき
When I lost confidence and collapsed,
キミの声がしたんだ
I heard your voice.
精一杯の迷い 矛盾だらけ迷宮の中で
Inside a labyrinth full of contradictions of my utmost hesitation,
等身大 キミに 未来の鍵を見つけ出して
true to life, find the key to the future for you!
No way どんな難題でも プレッシャーで弾き返せ
No way, no matter what difficult problem, bounce it back with pressure!
へこたれてたって まだまだぜ
Even if you get discouraged, you still have a long way to go!
3 2 1 ワンダフルハイハイ
3, 2, 1, wonderful high high!
諦めない 諦めないからさ
Never give up, never give up!
そう キミの前で 笑ってみせる
Yeah, in front of you, I act strong and show a smile,
強がりなぼくだけど
even though I'm just acting tough.
毛布の中 一人で 涙流す夜もある
But there are nights when I cry alone under the blanket,
孤独の戦士だ
acting as a lonely warrior.
自分に正直な 「やりたい」にまっすぐな
Being honest with myself, straightforward about what I want to do,
キミだけのヒーローでありたい
I want to be your only hero!
そうっと 孤独さを重ねて 駆け上がっていこう ねえ
Softly layering our loneliness, let's run up together, hey!
今はまだ 未知の途中
Now is still halfway through the unknown.
きっと 絶対諦めない
Surely, I will never give up!
ガンバってること知っているよ 涙のわけも知っているよ
I know you're doing your best; I know the reason for your tears too.
涙超えてゆけ
Beyond the tears, keep going...
for luck , for luck , for luck ! !
For luck, for luck, for luck!!
はあ、ぽつり漏れた
A sigh slipped out quietly...
幸せが逃げ出しそうで見失…ため息
Feeling like happiness is escaping, I sigh...
ねぇ鏡の中 無理な笑顔に唇歪む
Hey, in the mirror, my lips twist into a forced smile.
どうしてぼくだけ うまくいかないのかな
Why is it that things just don't go well for me?
ひとりよがりだとわかってる（わかるよ）
I know I'm being selfish (I know).
自信をなくして 崩れ落ちたとき
When I lost my confidence and collapsed,
ああ キミの声がしたんだ
Ah, I heard your voice.
精いっぱい 目いっぱい
With all my might, with all my heart,
矛盾だらけ 迷路の中で
In a maze full of contradictions,
等身大 Q . e . d .
Life-sized Q.E.D.
未来の鍵を見つけ出して
Find the key to the future,
no way ! ! どんな難題でも
No way!! No matter how difficult,
最適解で弾き返せ
Deflect it with the optimal solution!
へこたれたって まだまだ前進
Even if I get worn down, keep moving forward!
３、２、１で
3, 2, 1, and
fly high ! ! blow my tears
Fly high!! Blow my tears,
どこまでも 諦めないからさ
Wherever it may be, because I won't give up.
涙越えてゆけ for luck , for luck , for luck ! !
Beyond the tears, for luck, for luck, for luck!!
そう キミの前で笑って見せる
That's right, I'll smile in front of you.
強がりなぼくだけど
Even though I'm just acting tough.
毛布の中 一人で涙流す日もある
There are days I shed tears alone under the blankets.
孤独の戦士だ 自分に正直な
I'm a lonely warrior, being honest with myself.
「やりたい」にまっすぐな
Straight toward what I want to do,
キミだけのヒーローでありたい
I want to be your only hero.
（さあ行こう） 悔しさを重ねて
(Let's go) Accumulating frustrations,
駆け上がっていこうね
Let's run up together!
今はまだ未知・道・途中
Right now, we're still midway down an unknown path,
きこと絶対諦めない！！
Surely, I will never give up!!
ガンバってること知ってるよ 涙の理由も知ってるよ
I know you're trying your best, I know the reason for your tears.
博衣こより2周年ライブ見てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for watching Hakui Koyori's 2nd anniversary live!
ゲストさんとのプチトークがエンディングロールでありますのでチャンネルはこのままでお願いします！
There will be a chat with our guests in the ending roll, so please keep the channel as is!
お忙しい中出てくださったゲストの皆様に大きな拍手ーー！
A big round of applause to all the guests who took time out of their busy schedules!
そしてここで大切なお知らせです！
And now, here is an important announcement!
1曲目のオリジナル曲「アンバランス」はこのあとMVがプレミアム公開！24時から各種音楽サイトにてリリースされます！いっぱいい聞いてね！
The MV for our 1st original song "Unbalance" premieres right after, released at 24:00 on music sites!
そして2曲目のオリジナル曲「Tear-Gazer」は、emon(Tes.)さんに瀬名航さんに作詞作曲していただきましたー！
And our 2nd original song "Tear-Gazer" was written and composed by emon(Tes.) and Sena Kousuke!
この曲は2週連続リリースということで、来週12月5日の夜、12月6日の0時にリリースされるので、こちらも絶対ゲットしておリピして下さい！
Releasing two weeks in a row on Dec 5th night / Dec 6th 0:00, so please get it and loop it!
そしてお待たせかね！2周年記念グッズの紹介です！
And now, finally! Here is the introduction of the 2nd anniversary merchandise!
今回は…ついにでます！ももこママ描きおろしの「おっぱいマウスパッド」！
This time... it's finally coming! Momoko mama's newly illustrated "Oppai Mousepad"!
照れ動画が可愛すぎっ！大きさは…どうなるんだろういかに？
The shy video is too cute! How big is it going to be?
え、そして、おっぱいマウスパッドがあったら下半身も欲しいよね？ということで、
And if you have an oppai mousepad, you'd want the lower body too, right? So...
触り放題「しっぽクッション」発売！ふわもち素材で抱きしめて寝たらめちゃめちゃ気持ちいいよ！
Releasing the touchable "Tail Cushion"! Hugging it to sleep with fluffy material feels amazing!
さらに夏に公開して大好評だった新衣装のグッズ欲しいよね？という事で、
Also, you want new costume merch from summer that was super popular, right?
無乱先生描きおろしのめちゃかわアクリルキーホルダーもご用意しました！なぜかマヨネーズの着ぐるみを着ているこよも、まよらーも要チェックです！
We also prepared super cute acrylic keychains illustrated by Muran-sensei! Mayoral fans must check it out!
しっぽクッションと合わせて聞きたいシチュエーションボイス「しっぽのおはなし」も発売！こよがいつも触っちゃダメって言ってるしっぽを…ついに！？
Also releasing the situation voice "Tail Story" to enjoy with the tail cushion! Koyori's tail that you shouldn't touch... finally!?
そしてフルセットもございます！特典はメッセージとサインが入ったポストカードと、おっぱいマウスパッドのシチュエーションを楽しめるASMRボイス「ドキドキハプニングのおはなし」！数量限定ですまない！直筆サイン入りもありますよ！
Full set available! Bonuses include a signed postcard and ASMR voice "Heart-pounding Happening"!
え、コスカカード限定の笑顔もめちゃめちゃ可愛いので絶対ゲットしてくださいね！
The limited-smile postcard is super cute, so be sure to get it!
2周年記念グッズはこのあと22時頃から発売！使う用、保存用、布教用、なんでもゲットだ！
2nd anniversary merch goes on sale around 22:00! Get them for use, preservation, or spreading the word!
このあとメンバーシップ限定アンコールライブもありますので、そちらも遊びに来てね！今日は本当に御祝いありがとう！
There's also a membership-limited encore live after this, so come join! Thank you so much for celebrating today!
3年目のこよも止まねぇぞで頑張るので応援よろしくお願いします！女子くん大好きだぞ！うおーーーまっ！
Koyori's 3rd year won't stop either, so please keep supporting us! I love you guys! Wooah!
こよちゃん、2周年おめでとう！ありがとうございます！
Koyori-chan, congratulations on your 2nd anniversary! Thank you very much!
今こよ24で頭脳を見せつけてくださったお二人です！
These are the two who showed off their brains in Koyo24!
なんか位置取っちゃってちょっと、あの申し訳ないというか、ね、自分なんかしちゃいましたかって感じなんですけど。
I kind of took that position, feeling a bit apologetic like 'did I really do that?'
まあハーバードだから当たり前だよね？まあまあ、ホロライブの頭脳はアキロゼだからね！
Well, since you're Harvard it's natural, right? Well, Hololive's brain is Aki Rose!
いや、頭脳は私ませんからね！うおおお！
No, I won't hand over the brain title! Woohoo!
こよちゃん、2周年おめでとう！
Koyori-chan, congratulations on your 2nd anniversary!
記念すべきシンキュー！
A memorable thank you!
9Grounded4で大会優勝できたのめっちゃ嬉しかった！いや、皆様のおかげです！
I was so happy we won the tournament in 9Grounded4! Well, thanks to everyone!
また遊びましょうね！イエーイ！
Let's play again! Yay!
こより、ハッピーセカンドアニバーサリー！ありがとう！
Koyori, Happy Second Anniversary! Thank you!
日本に来た時、私に会いたいと言ってくれてありがとう。とても嬉しかったよ！
Thank you for saying you wanted to meet me when you came to Japan. I was so happy!
あなたが立てた素晴らしい目標が全て達成できる、素晴らしい一年になりますように。
May you have a wonderful year where all the wonderful goals you set are achieved.
そして、幸せであることを願っています。
And I wish for your happiness.
私だけでなくおそらく誰もが、あなたが皆に幸せを届け、
Because I believe not only me, but everyone knows
本当に一生懸命活動に取り組んでいること知っているからです。
you bring happiness to all and work extremely hard.
楽しさと元気いっぱいの幸せを願っています。そしてあなたがするすべてが成功するように。
I wish you a year full of fun and energy, and success in everything you do.
記念日おめでとう～！！
Happy anniversary!!
こよちゃんだいすき！ラブユー！！
I love you, Koyori! Love you!!
こよちゃん、2周年おめでとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Koyori-chan, congratulations on your 2nd anniversary! Thank you so much!
日ノ隈ラン先輩とライブで歌うのが夢だったんですが、この場を借りて夢を叶えさせてもらっちゃいました！
It was my dream to sing with Hinokuchi Ran-senpai live, and I got to make that dream come true!
本当？めちゃくちゃ嬉しいです！
Really? I'm so happy!
前からこよちゃんの歌枠でも歌ってもらったりとか、二人で歌枠コラボした時にも歌ったりね。
We've sung on Koyori's streams and done singing collabs before.
大事にしているこの曲を今日一緒にこよちゃんと歌えて良かったです。
I'm so glad we could sing this cherished song together today.
今日はゲスト呼んでくれてありがとう！また一緒に歌いましょう！やったあ、歌う！イエーイ！
Thanks for inviting me today! Let's sing together again! Yay, singing! Yay!
こよ、2周年おめでとうございます！ありがとうございます！
Koyo, congratulations on your 2nd anniversary! Thank you so much!
野球も連れていってくださって本当ありがとうございます！めちゃめちゃ楽しかったです！
Thank you so much for taking me to a baseball game too! It was super fun!
よかった！またみんなでどっか遊びに行こうね！やったあ、行く行く！
I'm glad! Let's all go hang out somewhere else again! Yay, let's go!
こより、2周年おめでとう！ありがとうございます！イエーイ！
Koyori, congratulations on your 2nd anniversary! Thank you! Yay!
実はもう2年にもなるので白上をするんですけど。ぺこら先輩のこと大好きなんです！
Actually, it's been 2 years so we're doing... but I love Pekora-senpai!
知ってたでしょ、ぺこ。え？何ですか？
You knew that, Peko. Eh? What is it?
こよりが誰にでも大好きって… 違いますよ！
Koyori tells anyone she loves them... That's not true!
こよりはほんとにぺこら先輩の憧れで大好きで、そうなの。
Koyori really admires and loves Pekora-senpai.
だからぺこりと会えた時に、こより真似してねってわざわざ言ってくれたの本当に嬉しかったんです！
When I met Pekori, she specially told me to imitate Koyori, which made me so happy!
本当です！本当です！じゃあこれからもよろしくね！
It's true! It's true! Well then, please treat me well from now on!
え、こちらこそよるぺこです！よるぺこです！よるぺこです！イエーイ！
Eh, same here, it's Yorupeko! Yorupeko! Yorupeko! Yay!
2周年ありがとう！今日という日を迎えられたのは、助手くんの応援のおかげだよ。
[Letter: Thank you for the 2nd anniversary! Reaching this day is thanks to assistant-kun's support.]